commercebank.com 2010-12-07

# Privacy Statement | Commerce Bank

## Commerce Bancshares, Inc. Privacy Policy Notice

Protecting your privacy is important to Commerce and to our employees. We want you to understand what information we collect and how we use it. In order to provide our customers with a broad range of financial products and services as effectively and conveniently as possible, we use technology to manage and maintain customer information. This policy serves as a standard for all Commerce employees for collection, use, retention and security of nonpublic personal information.

### What Information We Collect

We collect and use different types of information to service your accounts and to offer you better products and services that best meet your changing needs.

"Nonpublic personal information" is information about you and identified with you that we obtain in connection with providing a financial product or service to you. This is information which is unobtainable from a public source. For example, nonpublic personal information includes information regarding your account balance, payment history and overdraft history.

We may collect "nonpublic personal information" about you from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other loan and account forms;
  * Information about your transactions with us, our Affiliates, or others; and
  * Information we receive from third parties such as credit bureaus.

**Rest assured, we do not sell your nonpublic personal information to others.**

### How We Protect Your Information

We restrict access to your nonpublic personal information to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic and/or procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information.

### What Information We Disclose

We may disclose nonpublic personal information to companies that work for us and assist us in providing services to you. We may also disclose information as permitted or required by law. Disclosure of information in these circumstances is detailed below: 

**To service providers and for joint marketing:**

We may disclose the following information to third parties that provide services that assist us in servicing your loan or account with us, to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements: 

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, such as your name, address, social security number, assets and income; 
  * Information about transactions with us, our Affiliates, or others, such as your account balance, payment history, parties to transactions and credit card usage; and
  * Information we receive from credit bureaus, such as your creditworthiness and your payment history.

We have strict confidentiality agreements with all outside companies to ensure that they protect your information and never use it for other purposes.

**To other non-affiliated third parties:**

In addition, in certain circumstances we disclose nonpublic personal information about you to "nonaffiliated third parties" (i.e., third parties that are not members of our corporate family) as permitted by law. For example, we may disclose nonpublic personal information about you to third parties as necessary to process transactions that you have requested or authorized, to government entities in response to subpoenas and to credit bureaus. We do not disclose any nonpublic personal information about you to any other nonaffiliated third parties, except as permitted by law.

### Sharing With Affiliates

We are also permitted under law to share information about our experiences or transactions with you or your account (such as your account balance and your payment history with us) with our Affiliates. Our Affiliates include Commerce Banks, mortgage bankers, broker/dealers and insurance agents. By sharing information about your accounts and relationships among our corporate family, we can save you time and money and make it easier for you to do business with us. 

**Information about you we can share with Affiliates - unless you tell us not to:**

Unless you tell us not to, we also may share the following information about you or your account with our Affiliates: 

  * Information we obtain from your application, such as your income or marital status;
  * Information we obtain from a consumer report, such as your credit score or credit history;
  * Information we obtain to verify representations made by you, such as your open lines of credit; and
  * Information we obtain from a person regarding its employment, credit or other relationship with you, such as your employment history.

**How to tell us not to share this information with our Affiliates:**

If you prefer, you may direct us not to share this information with our Affiliates. If this is your choice, call us toll-free at 1-800-543-4845.

Note: Your direction in this paragraph covers certain information about you that we might otherwise share with our corporate family. We may share other information about you with our corporate family as permitted by law.

### Your Choice to Limit Marketing

One of the benefits of doing business with Commerce Bank and its Affiliates is the opportunity to effectively meet most of your financial needs – all in one place. We can do this by having our own brokerage and mortgage Affiliates, as well as student loan, trust and other financial services under one roof. This is the family of Commerce Bank companies, and through this corporate family we’re often able to offer you better value and convenience.

We understand that your time is limited and you are interested only in products that can provide a potential benefit to you. For that reason, we limit our marketing contacts to those complementary Commerce products and services that our research has shown may be of interest to you.

Commerce Bank and its Affiliates are providing this notice.

Federal law gives you the right to limit some but not all marketing from our Affiliates. Federal law also requires us to give you this notice to tell you about your choice to limit marketing from our Affiliates.

You may limit our Affiliates, such as our trust, mortgage, insurance and brokerage Affiliates, from marketing their products or services to you based on your personal information that we collect and share with them. This information includes your income, your account history with us and your credit score. Your choice to limit marketing offers from our affiliates will apply until you tell us to change your choice. If you have already made a choice to limit marketing offers from our Affiliates, you do not need to act again.

To limit marketing offers, contact us toll-free at 1-800-543-4845.

### Who Our Affiliates Are

As used in this Privacy Policy Notice, "Commerce" means Commerce Bancshares, Inc. and the members of the Commerce corporate family. Examples of Affiliates include the following financial service providers:

  * Commerce Bank, N.A.
  * The Commerce Trust Company, a division of Commerce Bank, N.A.
  * Commerce Brokerage Services, Inc.
  * Commerce Investment Advisors, Inc.
  * Commerce Mortgage Corp.
  * Commerce Insurance Services, Inc.
  * CBI Insurance Company
  * CBI Leasing, Inc.

### If You Cease To Be Our Customer

If you decide to close your account(s) or become an inactive customer, we will continue to adhere to the privacy policies and practices described in this notice.

#### Disclosures:

  * To send an email that contains confidential information, please visit the Secure Message Center where there are additional instructions about whether to use Secure Email or Online Banking messaging.
